I've often told the story of um meeting
his hor as his teacher in a train
station in India and he asked me what I
studying I didn't know and I just trying
to prevent that with your own students
in October don't forget uh say
G me means right G is the short name
for tick means commentary it comes from
Sans TI and uh the author of the booket
commentary has chosen to name his
book which means on theama which means
commentary on the
Gama so somebody says what's the main
book you're studying for your class
I'm uh
g means uh
what do you call it Regent it means the
person to whom the crown gets passed on
to when the King goes away okay so uh
jeton
Kaa
um as before he passed away he passed on
the lineage to G of J that's his
right-and man whenever you see a
painting of jeta with his two disciples
the one on his right which is your left
is always G of J okay so G of J means
the J means the great or the Lord like
jeta and g means y Raja young king in
Sanskrit which means the the region okay
the region so g j is the first holder of
the Throne of jeton Kaa after jetona
passed away and basically the thing with
jeffon compa and his students was he
would say look I don't have time to
write a cont on you do you know so
you'll see that all the major
commentaries done by just students like
the OB commentary by the first Dil they
are they are handling the places where
where Jess CER was too busy you you take
care of okay yeah I'll take care of
it um there's an interesting coincidence
here I'm sure it's just a
coincidence uh gup means region gup
means the person to whom you hand over
the kingdom after you leave and um I
don't know if you know but uh we are in
What's called the kalpa or the of Life
uh it's
calleda which means we in a fortunate
time during billion years of uh there's
this span of of the world of the
universe the universe contracts explodes
destroys and then it comes back into
being and that takes billions upon
billions and billions of years it's
called Uh
Donal don't is like billions and
billions of years in which the universe
empty and then there's Chuck say ch ch
means the universe starts to form then
there's means the universe is is um
staying for a while and then say j j j
means for billions of years it takes the
universe to die out and just reduce the
dust again so this whole process takes
billions upon billions and billions of
years and there's this sign way like
this of reality I mean going on during
time and only on one of the upswings
does a sorry one of the downswings does
a Buddha ever appear in the world like
only when things are going bad like when
there's violence in the world wars in
the world uh terrorist attacks in the
world uh pestilence plagues that that's
a good time for religion that's a good
time people start wondering about life
people start going to church again and
uh only during that tiny bit of time
does a Buddha ever appear and then a
thousand appear at once if you're lucky
and that's called a
DPA uh it's a kalpa of light and a
thousand Buddhas will appear on this
downswing now that we're on okay
thousand Buddhas
um shakuni Buddha the one who came to
India two and a half thousand years ago
was number three he was number three and
the next one coming is mraa okay so mraa
is the coming he's staying up in into
Shah Paradise okay and he's called the
what he's the G he's the G he's the
region before shakun Buddha comes to
this planet he turns over to sh Paradise
to and then he leaves see so I thought
it's sort of an interesting coincidence
that g
j the region wrote the book about the
Regent's book you know and um people ask
me how long will it take for my TR to
show up
um
in it says 49 billion
years okay
uh but there are other books you see
there's an argument about
M um and now I'm going to talk a little
bit about M tra see mrea is said to be
he was a bodh Saka during the time of
Lord Buddha he was just a play on bodh
Saka right he was one of near g means
one of the eight Great sons of Lord bhas
and then
um he saw emptiness and he started to
work up the bodhak boies bodhak levels
and um it said that he reached bhis
sappa level number 10 and that he's a
10th level bodh SAA and he's sitting in
t Paradise he's about to reach this
world okay um it's about to come into
this world and then there are other
books Tantra secret books they say look
oh my CH he was enlightened a long time
ago you know he was enlightened of years
ago this already
a and I guess what I wanted to say in
this regard is that
uh it's less than 500 years the next
Buddha is less than 500 years from now
and
U and to be frank you each one of you is
close enough uh you will be the next one
okay I I can say that you can say yeah
yeah you know I'm just I'm
busy you
know but I'll be very honest if you at
this cust hisory history if you on this
uh particular location at this
particular time um I say quite frankly
and I'm not being
uh I'm not just trying to be poetical or
something like that
you if you just keep going at your
normal pace
at this time you will be my chair you
will be the
next like you're that close you're
extremely close you're extremely close
each person here is extremely
close and you should think in terms of
of those when you think about your life
and you
feel dissatisfied with your life or you
feel like you're not doing much or you
feel
like you know just everyday life is too
much of a struggle you should stop that
thought
and you should say how can I set up the
world now for me for me to come into
this world see you have to think when
you walk around bu or Tucson or where
your house you have to think what can I
do today to prepare the world for my
this is going to be my world to teach
him you will be coming to this world as
the teacher as my TR and it's hard to
believe and you think oh you know I'm
busy and and you don't really believe
you think my TR some guy up in heaven
somewhere and he's got Chinese eyes for
sure and
uh it must be a lot more advanced than
me or I don't see how I could be the
next Buddha but you will be and that's
just the way it works and I tell you
that and now when you go out in the
world and you get as you work at your
job or even as you're with your family
when you wake up you have to think how
do I what's the best way I can prepare
the world for me I have to come you know
I've got a job to do on this planet I
will be coming to this planet I will be
coming to More Than This Planet how can
I in my lifetime prepare things what can
I do to do the best preparation for
myself because you will be
coming and that's the way it is and
you'll see it unfold and I can tell tell
you and you kind of don't believe me and
you think somebody wrote an email to
Ellie I think yes Michael needs a
psychiatric exam you
know but it's true it's true now how can
there be so many Mar on one plan at one
time
six questions are the
key this is not like a normal subject is
taught but I love I saw I read them over
again I said God we got to put this in
the course there a
Godly so we don't have much time we'll
go through them a little
fast
um but in my mind they got to be on
they're not a mistake at all and they're
not like some historical blip or
something they're really the whole
essence of the Gama is in the questions
the six questions so I'm going to read
them this is from uh a history book
written by a historian named
T who did a big his one of his biggest
contributions was to bring Buddhism to
Mongolia so all those who have been to
Mongolia it was really tanata he did
most of the
work oh I forgot I wanted to spell my's
name for him
before we get to the sixth question
say cha cha uh when you become a monk
and they give you your balls your first
name is normally the first name of the
person gave you your balls normally the
Abbot at the monastery gives all the BS
in the
monastery and normally the Abbot is
selected for a like threeyear
term so our Abbot when I was there in my
early years was named jum
di U and he got reelected four
times uh so for 12 years every monk in
the monastery who got B was named
Duma that made like 100 jumpers running
around the mon like people say I'm
jumpering 73 you know
the Juma in how is one of those Jas just
so you know J M um so Juma means love
Juma means love it's the desire to give
people everything they need it's the
desire to give people everything they
hope for that's called jumper so his
name my tra my tra means
love we talked about it in the yoga s
but my tra comes from a root M which
means to mix or to be friendly and um
like
KRA uh the old s which means spiritual
friend uh means that that came
into Latin as me from mink mink and then
it means to mingle or to get mixed
together so it means to be friendly or
to mix with people uh and my does just
that sometimes he's called uh J
[Music]
can you turn off the r just
it's
okay
say like some you heard people tiet
llamas with the word Jun in Fr Jun means
gentle it means uh the loving one J good
means protector the protector and in
Sans but it means the protect so you
might see J's name Mya's name sometimes
in books is it's the protector my
J sometimes he's called
meom meom means
unbeatable
unbeatable and that's a jit
in like I had a diamond in
a it means
undefeatable uh these are different
names that you might see use for my tra
these are all different names for my tra
I'll bu thr the Sun
he
it's good to have children here so you
need you have children you want to bring
okay to class
anytime we
might no it's very good to the
children so anytime
say
to to is a name in it's
called um to as we mentioned the other
night is to is to strike an obstacle
that you can't get through like that's
called
to and to man means you just pass
through it like winds like the wind you
know to me means I like to call it hot
maxel just put in your Thro so so to
means you know passes through obstacles
like
air and that's what a s's name mean ah
means man means not s means to get
stopped trying to get through something
and his mind was so powerful and he was
called a nothing could stop him no
problem could stop his mind he just go
right through it his name is
Mr lived around 350
I just wanted to say that
uh something about his position in our
lineage I think you know uh
[Applause]
you can split the L all the teachers of
the L the llas of the L can be basically
divided into G CH which
means activity side of the lineage and
then s which means the emptiness side of
the
lineage and this side of the lineage
comes down from Lord Buddha through M
and then the
mainly this side of the lineage comes
down to
mainly and
then you can
say but it it divides that way so in one
sense a a represents
the whole B St the side of our L lineage
so he's looked upon as like the
forefather of them you can also split
um all the the high schools
you can split the highest schools into
middle way and Min
only and there's this big deal called
the inventors you know the two inventors
like there are only two people in
history before J mapa that were
considered so important in the world as
to be considered like a second Buddha in
the world and they are Nara and a so nag
is considered the founder of the middle
way School in modern
times after the Buddha and then a is
considered like the founder of the Mind
only
school which makes the a mind only
practitioner
right yeah okay he's not he's not you
know he was predicted right he would
clean up the mess about the second and
third turs of the wheel he would clarify
what the really meant would have been
really mean you know
uh but in so doing he clarifies the
lower version of emptiness my so he's
remembered for them so his name is
attached to this side of the family so
that's two ways to look at
um how do we know he's an
Arya how do we know he saw have genus
directly uh there's a big debate in the
scriptures you know and I've been
reading some of the histories of s but
uh
some books say that when he got to T he
[Music]
gained yeah it's a kind of s it's a kind
of concentration When You Reach This
level you remember all the DS you ever
had for all your
lifetime just boom and it's it's very
noticeable like you start to recall
stuff you heard three or four years ago
and then 5 years ago then 10 years ago
and then you can Chace it back to the
beginning of your life things that you
were Tau but you get sometime deep
sbody where just everything you ever
heard like every ACI course you ever
heard you can quote pages from it and
and you know people here a lot of people
here have pieces of it you have hints of
it like just things pop in your mind and
you're able to roll things off your
tongue you've got a little taste that
you're give you think some of the R
treating since three retreat with Dan it
was very sweet to see it was really
powerful like there were people who
didn't know to Buton and then towards
the end of the retreat they got two
weeks training and they were reading to
they were able to just read it uh the
sounds like that you know and I felt
like they were getting CH but it's a
powerful sign and it comes do you
know uh
I'm sorry
yeah there's four levels to there's four
levels to the path just before you see
ESS
directly when you reach the third one
you get this kind of concentration when
you can recall things or you're like
super sensitive to Dharma and you get it
right away everything just flows into
your mind people say that Arya got that
when he stepped into TSH
Parise which is which makes sense
because then he got he was able to hear
my
tra uh but that also applies what he was
very close to see yeah implies he wasn't
in IR when he got to Tash he had not
seen
INF and I believe that's the case um
later other texts say he went on to to
reach the first bodhak level and CM this
directly after he was teaching for a
while after he came back and then most
books agree that by the end of his life
he had reached the Third body LEL they
say by comparison the guardian I reached
the first body
LEL and my tra in his current condition
has reached the 10th okay that'll be in
your reading you'll see some in the
readings for that
um but that's about how rare that is
it's extremely rare uh and that's that's
the kind
of that's kind of the amount of people
who do it
um so we call him AR never just call him
a so whenever you speak about him to
your students you should always say oh
AET is Pap
po I think Master is okay but Po's more
rare you
see I know there's a little thing about
Arya and Nazis and all that but you can
explain to people right so I think
that's all right I wanted to say one
more thing so we'll be studying Dela J
book
book but also uh Arya s later in his
life he thought it would be good to
write a
commentary on
G and so he did write a commentary and
it exists in Sanskrit we still have the
Sanskrit and we still have the and of
course we have the Tibetan so I'll be
teaching you a lot from uh Master's
commentary to what he heard directly
from master from my TR so you'll be
getting GTA Bas commentary which is
based heavily on ARA's
commentary and then how do you present a
12E course in 10
weekends
uh you know we use the GU Lama in the
debate ground in C we use it a not a lot
but we use it on special occasions in
certain difficult subjects we pull out a
Guama quotation poet go no start quoting
Gama like Gama is particularly known in
stere the best Monastery in the universe
for being effective in certain arguments
you know there's certain places where G
really tells you the bottom line on
something so what I thought for this
course is we pull out those
parts and so you're G to get the parts
of UL Lama based on A's text based on
GJ's text but pulled out from the places
where if you were a monk at C Monastery
you'd be arguing from Gama you see You'
be because on those questions G is most
powerful so we're going to be pulling
the course we're going to be extracting
the course out of where Lama comes up in
a typical Tibetan Monastery most often
with really powerful debates especially
about Buddha nature you know are you a
Buddha already or not what's the nature
of the Buddha inside of you know and
we'll be debating that okay back to the
six questions of the
kingom
and I'm just going to
read ra is a
question the king is beaming this ESP
question to can you hear
me can you answer this question okay
question is somebody came up to Lord
Buddha and
said bodh the word bodh is a word for
something else right what is it a word
for these are as you remember from the
other night the first three questions
are about
what the wording of the Perfection of
wisdom secret and the last two questions
are about the meaning of the Perfection
WIS so now we're on the words right so
somebody's asking Lord Buddha you
mentioned the B is that a word for
something
else did you mean something else what's
that a word for and Lord Budd
says
means don't
even don't even think that you can see a
body
St there's no body St you can't see a
St somebody ask what's a word for he
says don't even think you can
see didn't they
say was Lord Buddha giving one of those
non
answers okay we call him the 14 non
aners Lord Buddha got asked 14 questions
in his lifetime that he refused to
answer okay so they're proposing like is
that number 15 or something okay why did
Lord buha refuse to
answer is this a pen actually B
this morning earlier in the class I said
are you separate from me and what do you
say yeah he came back with a question
which is a debating tactic which is you
see Lum then means if he just sat there
and refused to
answer he'd be telling us you asked the
wrong question the question is
unanswerable as your question stands it
can't be answer yes or no okay is B
separate from
me you can't answer that yes or no until
the person says ultimately or
conventionally or apparently or
something like that okay so they're
called unanswered questions so the
King's first question is when Lord
Buddha refused to answer this question
about bod office or said you can't see
bod office anyway was he giving a new
unanswerable
question and master s says no he wasn't
he was just talking about the fact that
inside you are empty
inside meaning that bod Sapp
are can you is it really true you can't
see a bod Sapp no is it really true you
can't see a pen
No ultimately is it true you can't see a
pen yes that's all so he was talking
about the emptiness of a person of BU
that's all that's what he's talking
about second question
Buddha was talking about some big bird
he's got Wings span of 500 Y which is
750 miles okay what what's Lord buha
really talking about okay and the answer
on the next
page he was saying look if you want to
get into the business of dealing with
emptiness you're going to need a hell of
a lot of good kic your kic Wings have to
be 750 m one or you can't even you'll
sit here and you'll get bored to death
and you won't come back I mean it's not
only that reason but but in general to
listen to emptiness to understand
emptiness to give the right answer about
the
pen to have the karma to do that is
extremely rare extremely rare and you
guys all
have last question last of the three
questions
check this
out that's why I couldn't remember it
the other night
um when you see when you no longer see
any sign of the mountains and the
forests okay when you no longer see any
signs of the mountains and the
forest uh you will know you are close to
the
ocean what is the line at which you can
see the
sign what is the line at which you can
still see the sign I'll say it again
when you can see when you can no longer
see any sign of the forest of the
mountains and the forest you know you
are approaching the ocean what is the
line that which you still see the
sun just take a shot who wants to take a
shot what he talking about you want me
to say it again
uh what did I say oh when you no longer
see any sign of the mountains and the
forest you know you're getting close to
the ocean what's the line at which you
still see the sides maybe a moment when
you're noticing you're experiencing
directly and you start to wonder I'm
seeing directly
then close
yeah
direct yeah which
happens yeah in a minute like hour like
the hour that you see anything is
directly you reach Chicho and
specifically you reach what we called
chich ch ch cha means big stage Cho like
there's a lower stage Cho medium stage
ch choke and big station choke lower
station choke is like 2 hours before
middle stage is like an hour and a half
before choke CH occurs like the that's
the moment you see theend ination of the
PO directly are those three to four
parts of J it's it's the three parts of
the fourth quarter J yeah yeah so in J
when you get to big big level J just
before you see anus
directly uh would you you still be
seeing the signs signs means in Maj
language still seeing things that
self-existent would you still see the
signs yeah but you're getting close to
the ocean and and that's this that's the
line that's where the line is like
you're just coming out of the mountains
and the forest onto the beach and you're
just about to lay eyes on the ocean okay
let's see what a
said Sim the answer to the third
question is CH him ch
they gave the
answer it's exactly
what
answer origination depin yeah yeah last
moments of last moments of the just
before you
see so I answered that one now we go on
to the meaning this is a little harder
okay let's see how you guys do I fudged
it the other night over here cuz
everybody looked tired and wanted
Pizza not me of
course
uh find a
question I said the first question about
the meaning of by the way this is the
last part of the class so don't don't
lose hope yeah this will be the last
part of class but I say you got to go
back and kick ass on studying this stuff
or you're not going to make it with your
own students this first class is a
little
hard and
uh I said I I require that you not only
do the homework in quiz but that
somewhere time time before the next
class you discuss this class with one
other person okay could be
Andrea could be chil you know but so now
you got three jobs you got to prepare
for a quiz you got to do a homework and
you have to discuss this class with one
other person I don't care say 10 minutes
but you'll end up doing it for an hour
and it's really really cool it's really
not cool and then I'll you'll get a quiz
uh beginning of the next
class and you should finish all 10
classes you know the same old rules
apply you know that Miss more than two
classes you don't get a certificate for
this course and I don't want you
teaching at the YCA because you won't
know what you're teaching about so you
know it's really good if you can make
all 10 classes because now you got extra
pressure on you to do you got to teach
people this the last class is like a
week before the YMCA happens so you got
to be ready you did say
yeah
yeah it's okay what what about us for
folks who won't be in Arizona the whole
time uh if you in uh in a barbarian land
like Illinois and
you talk to me talk to me I mean
exceptions for Extraordinary things like
some people are flying to hell to get to
hear his holiness K his teachings and if
you you know talk to me about exceptions
but no exceptions but talk to
me that's the way
right I said the other nine does
Storehouse Consciousness exist or not
but the real question
was does Storehouse Consciousness exist
in a material way or
not the was more
sophisticated like asking a if
Storehouse Consciousness exists is easy
asking whether it exists
really is a whole another Bain right and
it's the bad question is the
Ben does the projector
exist is there a place in your mind that
seeds are rening and spewing out your
Reality by the way it comes from a DOT
at the heart smaller than the point
of because tiny
dark at the heart is spewing forth your
whole
universe there's a piece in your own
heart in the chakra in the heart that is
spewing forth every detail of this
universe as we
speak does that
exist Does the spew
exist I mean that's of course
because we're here
okay we're here that proves it but the
King was more sophisticated than that he
said does it exist really materially
substantially what do you think
a he's very
cool I'll read it here it's a very cool
answer it's a little complicated
the answer
is in a deceptive way in a deceptive way
it exists
substantially okay in an apparent way it
really exists that's a cool way to get
out it's about what said about the
same in Ultimate Way
which means
what there's no there's no state of mind
that exists
ultimately you know in a deceptive way
in an apparent way it exists
substanti in an ultimate way come on
there's no thought in the world that
exists that way what what you asking me
for okay he gave a really good answer
that's exactly what Ben said when he
said are you talking con conventional or
now you guys got to be able to explain
that through
old right if they can get to the
projector part is there a part of your
mind that's projecting this this room
yeah is there a part of your mind that's
projecting everybody in this room
yeah but are you also projecting that
projector
yeah is there any part of your mind
that's not being protected no come on
what asking that for okay that's how
your s is so you can explain
that I think what's really important
what's really really important don't
leave people with some philosophical
bull you know don't leave them with that
you know say what what's a good guy to
do with anything well when you walk out
of this room and you go into Fourth
Street to get your Mexican dinner and
lunch after this class and the guy
spills Coke on your lap just before
going back to class and teach the other
people right uh you got to think about
the projection you got to think about
the projection you know I'm projecting
this incompetent because I've been
incompetent to others you know and if I
get mad at his incompetence I'll come
back tomorrow and get another Co build
up so I'm going to help him clean it up
and I'm going to be calm and I'll go
back and explain to people about
projected Co things on
my and that's the point of talking about
projection that's the point I'm talking
about I mean you got to take people the
next step right I think that's what
distinguishes ACI from
other you know presentations sooner or
later people get tired of this
intellectual BS about oh everything's a
projection or not a projection or is
exist Does it doesn't matter but if it's
applied to your real life you know if
you could clean up your world like
taking a sponge and cleaning up the coat
you know uh then it's worth to go
through all these classes then it's
worth it no more irritating people in my
life that's a holy goal that's worth
everything you know and that's really
what people want uh last question
no Sor slow
Lord Buddha said that all things Lord
Buddha said that no existing object has
any nature of its
own was he also implying that not having
any nature of your own didn't have any
nature of it
own I'll say it
again Lord Buddha said no existing
object has any nature of his own what he
therefore implying that not having any
nature of your own doesn't have any
nature of its
own that's a no-brainer you know the is
emptiness empty yes yeah of course
okay I'll prove it I mean you can get up
and talk about emptiness and a certain
percentage of people in the room will
fall asleep see they they're perceiving
it as a boring irrelevant uninteresting
thing you know somebody else in the room
suddenly
they suddenly grasp it after the 10th or
100th time hearing it from gashi Michael
that this could be applied to that
irritating person that they live
with you know like suddenly it just
Dawns on them you know after all these
years you know he's talking about the
person I was staying with you know I
could apply this to in my own house you
know like my roommate is empty I don't
have to see them like this you know I
could see them as divine being if I
could just be more patient myself you
know um the fact that two different
people in the room can get two
completely opposite understandings of
emptiness proves that Emptiness is empty
empty okay so that's a no-brainer
everyone kep that one L don't forget to
bring it up to the way terms Bill's
COC
uh this one's tough good place to stop
Buddha
explained that it's not emptiness that
makes everything
empty Lord G have said it's not
emptiness that makes everything else
empty and the question
is
uh who who is it that doesn't make it
empty and what kind of empty doesn't it
make okay I'll say it again I'll say it
again this are tough question a pretty
cool
King Bo Budd
said
uh that there's nothing which makes
emptiness empty empty who is it that
doesn't make emptiness empty and what
kind of EMP doesn't it make
empty need it one more time
One More Time Lord Buddha said there's
nothing that makes that
empty I'm sorry I got to change it Lord
Buddha said it's not emptiness that
makes emptiness empty I'll say it again
Lord Buddha said it's not emptiness that
makes emptiness
empty what kind of emptiness was he
talking about it doesn't make EMP
empty EMP does not make
yeah and one kind of emptiness is not
made
empty let's put it this
way EMP that is not making things
empty here's an emptiness which is not
making things
empty Lord Budd said that emptiness
doesn't make things empty Lord Budd said
emptiness doesn't make things empty the
question of the King
was what's the emptiness that doesn't
make things empty and what's the
emptiness that it doesn't make
empty what kind of does not make things
of makes and what kind of emptiness that
is not made empty by it
you okay you guys I'll say it one more
time emptiness said Lord Buddha doesn't
make things empty the question of the
King was what kind of emptiness is it
that doesn't make things empty and what
kind of emptiness is it that it doesn't
make
into now you see why people didn't
include this in the letter
com I'll say one last
time said emptiness don't make emptiness
empty the question of the King was what
kind of emptiness was it that didn't
make things empty and what kind of
emptiness was it that wasn't
making you lose it let me see
[Music]
when we talk about the emptiness that
doesn't make things empty we're talking
this one here is the perception of empty
it's the mind that sees empty okay Lord
Buddha forgot to say the Mind
sees he just said emptiness doesn't make
emptiness empty he should have said the
perception of emptiness doesn't make EMP
sense okay so this one over here the one
it doesn't make emptiness empty what
Lord Buddha meant was the mind which
sees emptiness doesn't make emptiness
empty okay the the mind which sees
emptiness doesn't make emptiness
empty okay doesn't make things
empty the mind which sees the emptiness
of
things I I'll I'm going to shade it over
until you catch it okay you'll catch it
the mind which sees emptiness directly
isn't what made those things empty
getting
closer so what's the next natural
step not what's the state of mind okay
I'll say it again it's not the
perception empty that makes things empty
now where would I go from
there now the the natural question
between there would be well then what is
it that makes things empty if it's not
the perception of emptiness that makes
things
then what makes things
empty no there's no CA it's always been
that
way it's always he's the audience of the
last question and I'll state it from the
text here where is
he uh she made
sorry means emptiness is not something
that didn't used to exist and it started
to exist because you saw it that's all
that's what Al said come on everything's
been empty for
forever nothing makes emptiness empty
emptiness has always been
empty okay son is like come on that's a
trick question
that's why Lord Buddha said
what what was the original weird
quotation
um it's not emptiness that makes ESS
empty yeah nothing that causes EMP yes
okay okay we'll go over it again
Rebecca's
like that's how I my
carat uh Lord Buddha makes the statement
it ain't emptiness that makes emptiness
empty
the king says what the hell was he
talking about I says well first of all
this the first ESS he mentioned was the
perception of was understanding The
Emptiness of the pen and the waiter who
spills the coke on you okay and that
doesn't make things
empty mind that sees EMP does not make
things empty right because they've been
empty always come on man we talking
about making EMP come on things have
been empty all
okay so the King clarifies the third
question Al did God we have two three
it's amazing yeah is not mind
well of course it's
a because it's a thing to him so was it
wasn't it made by you said it's not
it's a good debate we take it home and
debate it okay that's the kind of
question that in the monastery the
teacher would say keep that in your mind
go to the bate ground tonight and cause
a lot of trouble and let me know what
happens that's exactly the kind of thing
you should take to your conversation if
you have and that's what the
conversation should be they shouldn't be
oh why
M you should go through the
controversies why the hell do you say
that of course is
it's a projection you know when an sees
EMP in the first moment of the EMP
where's it coming
from so the mind ising it right right so
EMP is by the Mind SE EMP right right so
didn't say that EMP didn't make EMP
right you know then you get people
that's how you debate we'll have a nice
debate Park
in so the trigger of the cavat is the
mind that sees EMP EMP itself
uh we'll stop yeah there a difference
between seeing directly
and
uh cool I think that's a
good
uh on on on next class second class was
the one reason uh why I'm very
interested in in this text it's all
based on the seven Diamond like
Visions the whole text uh the whole
structure of this whole book is called
uh the seven Diamond light Visions like
this is one of the only books I've ever
seen that explicitly mentions diamond
and the whole book is debated is is is
dedicated devoted to seven diamond is
Visions uh that's going to be the whole
structure of
and just to see that then I have a lot
more faith in this text so
um so I think uh you know stick around
for the second the second class will
start to go through the structure in the
seven seven Diamond M
Visions it's appropriate for
Diamond I think you got email so you got
to
let make a list of everyone this year
every Everybody give me your email okay
or your yeah
give your email email question I'm sorry
I just had the doctor and all that and
then double day decided that the book
had to be which they sat on for six
months had to be edited in one week and
that was last
week
that's okay uh I'm sorry to keep you leg
but most of you know that's the way it's
going to
go he's up for years
[Music]
[Applause]
fore
[Music]
you know people on this day they make
big butter sculptures and they pile the
altars with things and people make uh
satas and I think the greatest offering
you can make on this day is to talk
about empties and I think you just made
the greatest offering you can
make so be happy and have a nice dinner
right it's the dinner time